# DR. JENNIFER KUETER

#### SUMMARY

Dynamic professor brings 7 years of higher education and 28 years of teaching experience. A highly motivated employee with a desire to take on new challenges and meet the diverse needs of students. Strong work ethic, adaptability, and exceptional interpersonal skills. Encourages students to actively participate in all aspects of the educational process. Uses various assessment tools and strategies to improve instruction methods. Ready to contribute my expertise to the University of Missouri and help shape the future of education.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Adjunct Professor**

University of Missouri | Columbia, MO | August 2016 - present

- Developed and adjusted course content and syllabi to meet diverse student needs.
- Conducted office hours weekly to provide assistance with course material or address any questions or concerns from students.
- Assisted in curriculum design for new courses or programs based on current educational trends and standards.
- Supported students in achieving learning objectives.
- Researched best practices for effective teaching methods in order to improve instructional delivery.

## **Elementary Teacher**

Anchorage School District | Anchorage, AK | September 1995 - May 2023

- Engaged students and developed an understanding of content using focused instructional strategies and hands-on activities.
- Utilized technology-based learning tools to enhance instruction.
- Created, adapted, and modified learning materials to support student learning.
- Ensured student access using equity-based practices

#### Math Academic Alignment Committee

Anchorage School District | Anchorage, AK | August 2012 - May 2019

- Created Academic Plan for connecting math curriculum to Common Core standards.
- Created assessments and supplemental materials and resources to support implementation of standards.
- Facilitated district-based in-services on conceptual mathematics.

#### **Mentor Teacher**

Anchorage School District | Anchorage, AK | August 2000 - May 2023

- Supported the growth of preservice teachers through meaningful conversations focused on individual strengths.
- Advised on methods for effective teaching methodology to ensure productive classroom environments.
- Conducted regular one-on-one meetings with each mentee to discuss challenges, successes, and goals.

## REFERENCES

Dr. Jane Howland, Professor | University of Missouri | howlandj@missouri.edu
Dr. Bridget Miller, Professor | University of South Carolina | btmiller@mailbox.sc.edu
Marco Christian, Principal | Anchorage School District
| Christian\_Marco@asdk12.org

#### CONTACT

**3** 9077484576

jenkueterak@gmail.com Kueteri@missouri.edu

Anchorage, Alaska 99507

#### SKILLS

- Facilitating Professional Development
- Innovative Lesson Planning
- · NBPTS Certified
- Technology Integration
- Serving Diverse Communities
- · Flexible and Adaptive
- Accommodating for Special Needs
- · Collaborative Work

## EDUCATION AND TRAINING

## Ed.D

STEM Education University of South Carolina -Columbia, Columbia, SC June 2020 - August 2023

#### Ed.S

Information Science and Learning Technologies University of Missouri - Columbia, Columbia, MO

August 2013 - December 2015

#### **Master of Science**

Information Science and Learning Technologies University of Missouri - Columbia,

Columbia, MO

## August 200 - December 2002

Bachelor of Arts
Elementary Education
University of Iowa, Iowa City, IA
August 1990 - December 1994